<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>mind-voice</title>
    <subtitle>Grab a cup of coffee and hear me out.</subtitle>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://nithinsravan.github.io/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nithinsravan.github.io/"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2024-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://nithinsravan.github.io/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Hello World</title>
        <published>2024-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nithinsravan.github.io/blogs/blog-1/"/>
        <id>https://nithinsravan.github.io/blogs/blog-1/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://nithinsravan.github.io/blogs/blog-1/">&lt;p&gt;Hello World! Welcome to my blog. Never created content before. Feels new. But nobody tells you how excruciatingly painful it is to find the motivation to start something. Procrastination is so addicting. You want more of it every time. For the record this particular blog post was supposed to go out yesterday or maybe some 3 months ago. &lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;blogs&#x2F;blog_confusion_meme.png&quot; alt=&quot;blog  meme&quot; class=&quot;blog-images&quot;&#x2F;&gt;
That&#x27;s the thing with procrastination, you park your idea for really long you almost forget its existence. Now that I finally sat to do something about this, I was left with questions. Questions like, where should I start? What should I write? What&#x27;s for lunch? Will readers like my style of writing? What should I eat for dinner? Will I continue this blog? What should I name the blog? I have no answers for any of these. But it doesn&#x27;t matter because, here we are. My Hello World for blogs. Alright, but how did I finally make this happen?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;ssgs-for-blogs&quot;&gt;SSGs for blogs&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This site was created using a Static Site Generator (SSG) called &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.getzola.org&#x2F;documentation&#x2F;getting-started&#x2F;overview&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Zola&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. The junior-developer-me would want to create everything, including this blog site. If I had given in to my ego, I would&#x27;ve been writing code for the platform and not this post. &lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;blogs&#x2F;dev_blog_meme.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;blog  meme&quot; class=&quot;blog-images&quot;&#x2F;&gt; It sure is an exciting project to do. But my focus is on the content and developing the habit of blogging. In fact, I got sidetracked multiple times from actually producing content. With my 9 to 5 job already taking up 60-80% of my time, I had given up multiple times already. This was one of the major reasons I chose an SSG since this helped me speed up this process and help me focus on my goal amidst my generally tumultuous workday (plus I am lazy and c&#x27;mon...who am I kidding...skill issues).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SSGs are a great way to start your custom blog site. This lets you focus on the task and speed up the process of setting things up. I started using Zola to spin up my site using a theme.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zola is a static site generator (SSG), similar to Hugo, Pelican, and Jekyll (for a comprehensive list of SSGs, please see Jamstack). It is written in Rust and uses the Tera template engine, which is similar to Jinja2, Django templates, Liquid, and Twig.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Content is written in CommonMark, a strongly defined, highly compatible specification of Markdown. Zola uses pulldown-cmark to parse markdown files. The goal of this library is 100% compliance with the CommonMark spec. It adds a few additional features such as parsing footnotes, Github flavored tables, Github flavored task lists and strikethrough.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting Zola up and running on your machine is pretty straightforward. The initial setup and configurations might take some effort and time depending on your blogging requirements. But a huge coding effort is easily handled by the SSG and the rest is just styling, configuring, and handling data. Finally, choose your method of deployment and voila your blog is ready to go. I used &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.getzola.org&#x2F;documentation&#x2F;deployment&#x2F;github-pages&#x2F;&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to deploy my site.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-this-blog&quot;&gt;Why this blog?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog is a way for me to help myself grow and explore more stuff. I wish to focus majorly on tech, but I do plan to sneak in some non-tech posts, where I talk about my interests, hot takes, and more. So stay tuned folks. Until next time. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
